<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Recipes | azure sky]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/categories/recipes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.azuresky.ca/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-02T11:02:24+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.azuresky.ca/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Chang]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[michael.chang@azuresky.ca]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oven-Baked Hard-Boiled Eggs]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/04/oven-baked-hard-boiled-eggs/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-02T10:52:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/04/oven-baked-hard-boiled-eggs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Adapted from <a href="http://www.food.com/recipe/hard-cooked-eggs-in-the-oven-baked-eggs-61856">food.com</a></em></p>

<ol>
<li>Place oven rack in the center of the oven. Place <strong>eggs</strong> on the racks.</li>
<li>Place a <strong>cookie sheet</strong> (lined with foil!) underneath the eggs... just in
case one explodes, cracks, or leaks while cooking.</li>
<li>Set oven to <strong>325 &deg;F</strong> for <strong>30 minutes</strong>.</li>
<li>Remove eggs from oven and place in <strong>ice-cold water</strong>. Peel as soon as they
are cool enough to handle, then return to the water to thoroughly chill.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Tips and Suggestions</h2>

<ul>
<li>How many eggs? About a dozen is about right. Too few (less than six) and
you're probably better off with a pot of water; too many (two dozen or more)
and your oven will be a bit crowded.</li>
<li>No ice? Instead, place the bowl in the sink, and leave the water running over
the eggs.</li>
<li>Too many hard-boiled eggs? Try making <a href="/blog/2012/04/simple-egg-salad/">egg salad</a>!</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Egg Salad]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/04/simple-egg-salad/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-02T10:48:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/04/simple-egg-salad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Coarsely chop <strong>6 hard-boiled eggs</strong>. A butter knife works well for this.</li>
<li>Add <strong>2 tablespoons mayonaise</strong>.</li>
<li>Mix well. Serve.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Tips and Suggestions</h2>

<ul>
<li>For the adventureous, try adding a dash of curry or paprika before mixing.</li>
<li>Real mayonaise is better than "salad dressing".</li>
<li>Some like to add finely chopped celery to egg salad. I find it messes up the
texture, but your mileage may vary.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oven-Baked Grilled Cheese]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/02/oven-baked-grilled-cheese/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-25T08:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/02/oven-baked-grilled-cheese</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to <strong>400 F (205 C)</strong></li>
<li>Line a <strong>cookie sheet</strong> with <strong>aluminum foil</strong>.</li>
<li>Spread <strong>four slices of bread</strong> with <strong>mayonaise</strong> on the "outer"
edges (since you'll be making sandwiches).</li>
<li>Place a <strong>cheese slice</strong> between each pair of slices of bread,
laying the sandwiches on the cookie sheet.</li>
<li>Bake for <strong>four to six minutes</strong>, then <strong>flip</strong> the sandwiches
and bake for <strong>another three to five minutes</strong>. Note that the
sandwich will brown on the bottom (the side facing the foil), and
not on the visible (top) side when it's in the oven.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Tips and Suggestions</h2>

<ul>
<li>Use real mayonaise, not "salad dressing", as this intended to
promote browning and needs a decent fat content. If mayonaise is
not available, you could probably substitute margarine or butter.</li>
<li>I tested this with "Thin Sandwich" bread, which has 24 slices in a
single loaf, and with "Thick" cheese slices. You'll want to adjust
the baking time and temperature if using something different.</li>
<li>You can probably fit three sandwiches on a cookie sheet, but I
can't eat that much all at once.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bacon-Wrapped Asparagus]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/02/bacon-wrapped-asparagus/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-25T08:24:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/02/bacon-wrapped-asparagus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to <strong>400 F (205 C)</strong></li>
<li>Line a <strong>cookie sheet</strong> with <strong>aluminum foil</strong>.</li>
<li>Wash <strong>10 asparagus shoots (about half a bunch)</strong> and trim the
bottom 1cm.</li>
<li>Wrap each asparagus shoot with a <strong>slice of bacon</strong> in a single
helix, and lay on the wrapped asparagus on the lined cookie
sheet in a single layer.</li>
<li>Bake for about <strong>20 minutes</strong> until bacon is cooked to desired
doneness.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Tips and Suggestions</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>Sometimes I prepare this at 375 F (190 C) to match another dish in
the oven. You may need to bake for a little longer if you do this.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Variant</strong>: Cover half of the shoots with <strong>barbeque sauce</strong>.
I've tried using Diana&reg; Sauce (Maple), though substituting
another variety should work. It's normal for a small amount of the
sauce to start charring on the foil. I find that covering all the
shoots with barbeque sauce is intoxicatingly rich, so I don't
usually do it if I plan on eating them all by myself.</p></li>
<li><p>If not serving immediately, drain excess bacon fat either
into the trash or into a bowl for later use. (Do not put down the
drain, as it will usually clog.)</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oreo Cheesecake Cupcakes]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/02/oreo-cheesecake-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-14T01:04:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.azuresky.ca/blog/2012/02/oreo-cheesecake-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to <strong>275 F (135 C)</strong>.</li>
<li>Line <strong>16 muffin tins</strong> with paper liners. (Fill empty slots in a
muffin tin with water.)</li>
<li>Place <strong>one Oreo (whole)</strong> in the bottom of each of the sixteen cups.</li>
<li>Beat <strong>2 8-oz packages cream cheese</strong>.</li>
<li>Gradually beat in <strong>1/2 cup sugar</strong> and <strong>1/2 teaspoon vanilla</strong>.</li>
<li>Gradually pour in <strong>2 large eggs, lightly beaten</strong>.</li>
<li>Beat in <strong>1/2 cup sour cream</strong> and a <strong>pinch of salt</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Pour</strong> batter into the tins, filling each almost to the top.</li>
<li><strong>Bake</strong>, rotating pan halfway through, until filling is set (about
22-25 minutes).</li>
<li><strong>Cool</strong> in pans at least 15 minutes, then <strong>refrigerate</strong> at least
four hours.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Tips and Suggestions</h2>

<ul>
<li>If you're okay with shorter cheesecakes, you could probably split
the batter over 18 tins instead of 16, though you'll need two more
Oreo cookies.</li>
<li>If you do fill the empty cups with water, remove the cheesecakes
before refrigerating, and set them on a cloth towel on a plate, as
moisture will accumulate on the bottoms if left in the pan.</li>
<li>Consider mixing in dried fruit, like dried cranberries.</li>
<li>Try piping strawberry jelly through a plastic bag to decorate the
cheesecakes prior to baking.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
